# Sarang Baheti

## Summary

Principal Software Engineer, specializing in developing Large Scale CAD Software and curious about technology in general.

I love solving hard problems, learning new domains and creating applications that are manageable and amenable to change. I have 14+ years of experience developing CAD systems in C/C++/C# languages, with focus on: Architecture, Performance, Graphics, Load/Save, Geometry & Interop.

# **Experience**

### Siemens PLM Software Inc, Cypress CA

July 2012 - Current

Working in Assembly Modeling Team as a Principal Software Engineer

- 1. Lead Developer and Architect for VisAtlas Initiative
- 2. Lead Developer and Architect for 4GD Routing Application
- 3. Architect for MultiCAD, Jt & Facets in NX. Member of NX Architects Team
- 4. I help coordinate OSS and third-party integration across various Applications and Geographically dispersed teams
- 5. Mentoring team members, tools development, helping with autotest/unittest regression analysis and builds is something I do on the side all the time

#### Autodesk Pte Ltd, Singapore

Nov 2010 - May 2012

Worked in PSEB (Platform Solutions) division as Senior Software Engineer

- Developed Arrays functionality in AutoCAD 2012 along with a few handy plugins for Law based curve creation and Prototype to declaratively and visually modeling a user defined features using WWF (Windows Workflow Foundation) and ObjectARX Framework
- 2. Worked on DesginScript (now <u>DynamoDS</u>) then a research project for associative scripting language

#### Siemens PLM Software Pvt Ltd, Pune India

Jun 2005 - Oct 2010

Worked as Software Engineer in Assemblies Modeling Team

- 1. Lead Developer for LightWeight/Jt Facets Usability in NX75/NX8
- 2. Lead Developer for Enhancing Flexible Components in NX6
- 3. Utility Projects like Part Close Enhancements, File New Dialog and Migration Reporting Enhancements during NX404-NX5 releases

### **Skills**

#### Expert in:

- C, C++ & NX & Jt Development
- Parasolid & JTTK Integration
- NX, TeamCenter, TcVis, 4GD & Routing Application
- Visual Studio IDE and Tools
- Performance Analysis and Tuning
- MultiThreading, Asynchronous Programming

#### Proficient in:

- WPF, .NET & Qt Framework
- Python, C#
- Linux/UNIX programming and scripting
- Source control with Git, Perforce

### **Education**

### M Tech, Mechanical Engineering

Aug 2004 - Jul 2006

Completed Masters with specialization Design Engineering from VJTI Mumbai with 78.5%

#### B. E. Mechanical Engineering

Jul 1999 - May 2003

Completed Bachelor of Engineering from Bharati Vidyapeeth's CoE Pune with 61%